

□ (+86) 13065123348 | 🔀 kangfumei@link.cuhk.edu.cn | 💣 mkfmiku.github.io | 🖸 MKFMIKU

# Summary\_

My main research interests include image processing, degraded images adapted high-level vision, and general image enhancement. I'm familiar with software development using Python and JavaScript, as well as other commonly used programming languages and frameworks. Besides, I have experience in cooperating with others in both industry and open-source communities.

# **Education**

#### The Chinese University of Hong Kong, Shenzhen (SSE)

Shenzhen

COMPUTER INFORMATION ENGINEERING - FIRST YEAR M.PHIL

Sep. 2019 - Jun. 2021

- AIM2019 Raw Image to RGB Image Challenge (ICCV2019 Workshop) Winning Award & Top 1
- 2019 Alibaba Youku Video Enhancement and Super-Resolution Challenge Top 4

# Jiangxi Normal University (CITE)

Nangchang

COMPUTER SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY - BACHELOR

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

- 2018 NTIRE2018 Image Dehazing Challenge (CVPR2018 Workshop) Honorable Mention Award & Top 6
- · 2018 University Computer Software Programming Challenge in Pearl River Delta Gold Award & Best innovative Award

# **Experience**

#### JD.COM

SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE ENGINEER INTERN

Jul 2017 - Nov 2017

• Worked on Intelligent Poster Generation System as a software engineer.

#### KuaiShou

IMAGE ALGORITHM ENGINEER INTERN

Jul. 2018 - Jun. 2019

· Worked on improving the latest image enhancement algorithms from academic research into practical application.

#### DAMO Academy, Alibaba-Inc

RESEARCH INTERN

Jul. 2020 - Present

• Working on the research of general image/video processing algorithms by Deep Learning.

# Publication

#### Disentangle Perceptual Learning through Online Contrastive Learning (Arxiv)

KANGFU MEI, Yao Lu, Qiaosi Yi, Haoyu Wu, Juncheng Li, Rui Huang\*

2020

### HighEr-Resolution Network for Image Demosaicing and Enhancing (ICCV2019W)

KANGFU MEI, JUNCHENG LI, JIAJIE ZHANG, HAOYU WU, JIE LI, RUI HUANG\*

2019

# Residual Refine based Pseudo Multi-frame Network for Effective Single Image Super Resolution (IET IMAGE PROCESSING)

KANGFU MEI, AIWEN JIANG\*, JUNCHENG LI, JIHUA YE, MINGWEN WANG

2018

## Progressive Feature Fusion Network for Realistic Image Dehazing (ACCV2018)

KANGFU MEI, AIWEN JIANG\*, JUNCHENG LI, JIHUA YE, MINGWEN WANG

2018

# An effective single-image super-resolution model using squeeze-and-excitation networks (ICONIP)

KANGFU MEI, AIWEN JIANG\*, JUNCHENG LI, JIHUA YE, MINGWEN WANG

2018

## Multi-scale Residual Network for Image Super-Resolution (ECCV2018)

JUNCHENG LI, FAMING FANG\*, KANGFU MEI, GUIXU ZHANG

2018

## Research

#### Relations Exploration between The Low-level and High-level Vision Tasks

LEADER Jul. 2018 - Present

• In this research, my works mainly focus on improving the low-level vision tasks, e.g., super-resolution, de-hazing, and enlighten with high-level vision features. My recent works have achieved state-of-the-art image enhancement performance with proposed contrastive-learning based high-level features only, as well as more generated visual pleasant details. Besides, my recent works successfully improved the accuracy of semantic segmentation problem under the haze/fog weather. These works are submitted to NeruIPS and TMM for review now.

JULY 28, 2020 KANGFU MEI · RÉSUMÉ 1